thegreatbritishbakeoff.co.uk 2019-04-03

# Privacy Policy | The Great British Bake Off

You are viewing this website with an old browser please update to a newer version of Internet Explorer [here](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-gb/internet-explorer/ie-10-worldwide-languages).

Please read this Privacy Policy to understand how Love Productions Limited use and protect the information that you provide to us via websites and online platforms relating to The Great British Bake Off, An Extra Slice and other related programming (collectively the “Programme”) including without limitation the website with domain name: thegreatbritishbakeoff.uk (the “Website”) and/or any account or pages created and/or operated by Love Productions Limited, on online platforms such as twitter.com, facebook.com and instagram.com using #GBBO, @BritishBakeOff and/or #ExtraSlice or on any Programme-related pages (the “Love GBBO Pages(s)”). The Website and Love GBBO Pages are hereinafter collectively referred to as the “GBBO Site(s)”.

In this Privacy Policy “we”, “us” & “our” refers to Love Productions Ltd whose registered address is at Grant Way, Isleworth, Middlesex TW7 5QD and its assignees, licensees and affiliates, and, where appropriate, to the creators of and contributors to the construction of the GBBO Site(s) and their contents; “you”, “your” & “yourself” refers to visitors to and users of the GBBO Sites and its content and, where appropriate, persons submitting personal information, recipes, photographs and other material thereto.

IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND YOU DO NOT WISH FOR YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO BE COLLECTED, USED AND TRANSFERRED IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE EXIT THE GBBO SITES IMMEDIATELY.

**1\. Introduction**

1.1          This Privacy Policy forms part of, and should be read in conjunction with, the [Terms and Conditions](https://thegreatbritishbakeoff.co.uk/terms-and-conditions/) for the GBBO Sites (“the Terms and Conditions”) and our [Cookies Policy](https://thegreatbritishbakeoff.co.uk/cookie-policy/) (“the Cookies Policy”). All capitalized definitions used in this Privacy Policy shall have the same meaning as ascribed to such definitions under the Terms and Conditions unless otherwise stated.

1.2           This Privacy Policy applies to personal information collected about you as a result of your use of the GBBO Sites and held, stored and processed by us whether in hard copy or in digital/ electronic form. We are the data controller in relation to all such personal information.

1.3           If you are accessing any of the Love GBBO Pages, you should also read the privacy policy and terms and conditions pertaining to the relevant platform on which the Love GBBO Page sits. The GBBO Sites may also contain links to other websites or platforms (such as twitter or Facebook) over which we have no control and/or you may access the GBBO Site(s) via links on other these third party sites/ platforms, including Programme-related webpages on www.channel4.com and www.All4.com (the “C4 Pages”). We are not responsible for privacy and data protection policies on those other websites/ platforms and/or on the C4 Pages. We encourage you to review the privacy policies on these other websites and platforms and the C4 Pages so you can understand how they collect, store, use and share your information. This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected through the GBBO Sites only.

1.4         The capture, storage and use of your data is governed by Data Protection Act 2018 and the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679. We are committed to safeguarding your personal information in a confidential and secure environment. We are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office (“ICO”) as a data controller, with registration number ZA048993. Our registration can be confirmed by searching the [Register of Data Controllers](https://ico.org.uk/about-the-ico/what-we-do/register-of-fee-payers/) on the ICO website.

1.5           We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy (or any part of it) at any time without prior notice. If we make any changes, we will publish the updated Privacy Notice on the Website.

**2\. What Personal Information do we collect and why?**

2.1           “Personal Information” is information relating to you, which can be used to personally identify you (either directly or indirectly). The types of Personal Information we may collect about you include any Personal Information you submit onto any of the GBBO Sites or otherwise send to us and/or any information you are asked by us to provide including but not limited to your name, user name (whether or not you have identified yourself by your real name or otherwise), place of origin, email address, other contact information, recipes, photographs, tweets, posts and/or any other information you may choose to submit to the GBBO Sites. We collect this Personal Information so that it can be used for the purposes set out in the Terms and Conditions. We may for example publish amusing or interesting tweets in any Programme or invite you to submit examples of your bakes on any GBBO Site for potential inclusion in any Programme and/or other initiatives.

2.2           We may also collect information about your usage of the GBBO Sites, such as browsing patterns, but information collected in this way will not identify you personally. Our servers also automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. This may include your web request, internet protocol address, browser type, browser language, URLs, URLs domain names, pages viewed and other matters together with cookies which may identify your browser. We use this information to find out about how visitors use the GBBO Sites.

**3\. What is our lawful basis for using your Personal Information?**

3.1           We will only use your Personal Information when we have a valid reason (also known as a ‘lawful basis’) to do so. Which legal basis is applicable will depend on precisely how we are using your Personal Information and for what purpose.

3.2           Most commonly, we will use your Personal Information:

  1. a) because it is necessary to pursue our legitimate interests and where there is no undue adverse impact on you;
  2. b) in order to comply with a legal obligation to which we are subject;
  3. c) because you have consented to us doing so

3.3           Where we are processing your Personal Information for the purposes of pursuing our legitimate interests, those interests may include:

(a)            responding to any queries you may have, providing you with information you request and/or to help us operate and improve the GBBO Sites;

(b)            the development, production, exhibition, exploitation, distribution, advertising, publicity and promotion of the Programme and your contribution to the Programme;

(c)         identifying you when you contact us or use any of the GBBO Sites;

(d)            describing and identifying you when using any information you submit or otherwise in accordance with the Rights granted under the Terms and Conditions and to accord you credit therefor;

(e)            establishing, exercising or defending legal claims;

(f)              monitoring and managing access to our systems;

(g)             protecting our networks and your Personal Information;

(h)            investigating and preventing fraud;

(i)              co-operating with investigations by regulatory bodies and/or the police or other law enforcement agencies and/or governmental agencies; and

(j)              compiling, aggregating and disclosing to third parties general demographic information – this information may relate to age, gender, location etc. but will not specifically identify you or your computer personally.

**4\. How may we share your Personal Information?**

4.1           We may share your Personal Information with third party companies, agents, contractors, service providers or affiliated companies but only insofar as is necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We may share your Personal Information with law enforcement agencies, other governmental agencies or other third parties if we are required by law to do so. We may also share your Personal Information with our professional advisors.

4.2          Should a third party acquire all or a substantial portion of our business (whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets, or as part of any insolvency where such a transaction has been approved by the court) we may include your Personal Information then in our possession as part of the transferred business assets in such sale/ transfer and share the same with our advisors and any prospective purchasers and their advisors.

4.3           Where we transfer your Personal Information outside the EEA we will ensure that it is protected and transferred in a manner consistent with legal requirements applicable to the Personal Information concerned. This can be done in a number of different ways, for example: the country to which we send the Personal Information may have been assessed by the European Commission as providing an “adequate” level of protection for personal data; the recipient may have signed a contract based on standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission; where the recipient is located in the US, it may be a certified member of the EU-US Privacy Shield scheme. In other circumstances, the law may permit us to otherwise transfer your Personal Information outside the EEA. In all cases, however, any transfer of your Personal Information will be compliant with applicable data protection law.

4.4      In accordance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (commonly referred to as COPPA), we do not require children under the age of 13 to provide us with any more information than is reasonably necessary to make use of the GBBO Sites and under no circumstances do we require children under the age of 13 to provide us with any Personal Information. Children under the age of 13 should not submit or post any Personal Information without the written consent of their parents or legal guardians. If you are a child under the age of 13 and want to submit your Personal Information to us, you should ask your parents to send an email to [datasupport@loveproductions.co.uk](mailto:datasupport@loveproductions.co.uk) specifically allowing us to collect your Personal Information through this site. By doing so, you allow us to alert your parent or guardian about this Privacy Policy. We do not intend to sell, license or trade any such Personal Information collected, to third parties. Parents may review or change the Personal Information of their children provided to us or further refuse our collection of such Personal Information by sending an email to datasupport@loveproductions.co.uk.

**5\. Security and retention of Personal Information**

5.1           We have implemented appropriate technical measures designed to secure your Personal Information from accidental loss and from unauthorised access, use, alteration or disclosure, including encryption, firewalls and secure socket layers. Notwithstanding such measures, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorised third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your Personal Information for improper purposes.

5.2           We shall retain your Personal Information as follows: (i) in respect of any Public User Material (as defined in the Terms and Conditions) submitted by you via the GBBO Sites: for the length of time that the GBBO Sites are available to the public and/ or if used in any of our Programmes: for as long as is necessary in order to produce, market, distribute, exhibit, exploit, publicise, promote and/or advertise the Programme and to comply with our obligations to any broadcaster or distributor or other licensee authorised to do the same; or (ii) in respect of any Non-Public User Material sent to us by you via any of the GBBO Sites for 6 months from the date of submission or as long as necessary to address the purpose for which they have been sent; unless you request that your Personal Information is deleted (see clause 6.1 below). .

**6\. Your rights in respect of your Personal Information**

6.1           Under EU data protection laws you have a number of rights in relation to your personal data. Those rights include the right to:

  1. a) access your Personal Information (via what is commonly known as a “data subject access request”);
  2. b) require us to correct any mistakes in your Personal Information which we hold;
  3. c) withdraw your consent if we are relying on consent as our lawful basis for using your Personal Information;
  4. d) require the erasure of your Personal Information;
  5. e) require us to restrict processing of your Personal Information, in certain circumstances;
  6. f) receive the Personal Information you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or transmit that information to a third party, in certain situations; and
  7. g) object to our continued processing of your Personal Information if such processing is carried out for the purpose of our legitimate interests;

6.2           Please note that not all of these rights are absolute – in some cases they will not apply to you, or to the particular use that we are making of your Personal Information (for example if we have to process the information to comply with our own legal obligations). For further information on each of these rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, please contact us or see the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals’ rights under the General Data Protection Regulation here: <https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/>. If you wish to access a copy of your Personal information or exercise any of your other rights your request must be made in writing and we will endeavour to respond within a reasonable period and in any event within one month in compliance with applicable data protection legislation.

6.3           We are reliant on you to ensure that the Personal Information you provide to us is up to date and accurate, and you agree to provide true and accurate information about yourself as requested by us. To assist us in ensuring your Personal Information is up to date, please let us know if any of your personal details change by emailing us at [datasupport@loveproductions.co.uk](mailto:datasupport@loveproductions.co.uk).

**7\. Cookies**

Please see our separate [Cookies Policy](https://thegreatbritishbakeoff.co.uk/cookie-policy/) for details of cookies in use on GBBO Sites.

**8\. Monitoring**

We may monitor and record any communications we receive from you. This may be done to improve the services which we provide or to ensure compliance with our practices and procedures.

**9\. Jurisdiction**

This Privacy Policy will be exclusively governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of England and will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English courts.

**10\. Contact Us**

If, at any time, you have issues or concerns about the Privacy Policy or believe that we have not adhered it, please email our Data Protection Officer at [dataprotectionofficer@loveproductions.co.uk](mailto:dataprotectionofficer@loveproductions.co.uk). We will use reasonable efforts to answer promptly your question or resolve your problem. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the ICO if you feel any concern of yours relating to this Privacy Notice has not been dealt with properly. The ICO may be contacted at [https://ico.org.uk/concerns](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/).

**Last updated January 2019**

**© Love Productions 2019**
